Dudley Harmon Papers, 1920-1967
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Dudley Harmon Papers
1920-1967
Harmon, Dudley, 1912-1966
MS 191
2 boxes (1 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Journalist and war correspondent. Papers consist of correspondence, writings, biographical material, photographs and memorabilia. Includes letters home during World War II; her coverage of the Nuremburg trials and the United Nations European Headquarters in Geneva; and her letters and journal from Brazzaville, French Equatorial Africa. Also included are unpublished stories, radio broadcasts, two scrapbooks and letters to her father.
Biographical Note
Dudley Harmon was born in Washington, D.C., November 9, 1912, to Dudley and Selene Armstrong Harmon, both journalists. After graduating cum laude from Smith College in 1934, she began her career as a society columnist for the Washington Post. Resigning in 1941, Harmon went to work for the Free French in Brazzaville, French Equatorial Africa, where she also served as a correspondent for the Christian Science Monitor. Her next location was in London, in 1942, as Director of Public Relations for the U.S. War Shipping Administration. She joined the United Press in 1943 as one of their first female foreign correspondents during World War II. From 1943 to 1952, she was assigned to London, Paris, and Washington. She covered the Nuremburg Trials in 1946, and reported from the United Nations European headquarters in Geneva from 1948 to 1952. Harmon also served as a member of the United Press staff covering the U.N. General Assemblies in 1948 and 1950.
Returning to this country in 1952, after nine years with the United Press, Harmon worked as Acting Publicity Director for the League of Women Voters in Washington, D.C., as a consultant to the Ford Foundation in New York City, and as Acting Publicity Director for Sarah Lawrence College. She returned to Smith College in 1955 to assume the position of News Director. In 1962, Harmon was named Manager of Information Services for CBS News, Washington Bureau, the post she held until she died on September 14, 1966.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Harmon papers consist of correspondence, writings, biographical material, photographs and memorabilia. Of particular interest are her letters home from overseas during World War II; her published newspaper and journal articles including her coverage of the Nuremburg trials (1946) and the United Nations European Headquarters in Geneva (1948-52); and her letters and journal from Brazzaville, French Equatorial Africa (1941-42). There are also unpublished stories, radio broadcasts, two scrapbooks and letters to her father.
Organization of the Collection
This collection is organized into five series:
I. Correspondence
II. Writings
III. Biographical Information
IV. Photographs
V. Memorabilia
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The Papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
Search Terms
Harmon, Dudley, 1912-1966; League of Women Voters--History--Sources; Nuremberg Trial of Major German War Criminals, Nuremberg, Germany, 1945-1946--Sources; Smith College--Students--History--Sources; United Nations--History--Sources; Brazzaville (Congo)--History--Sources; Women journalists--United States--History--20th century--Sources; World War, 1939-1945--Journalists--Personal narratives, American
Additional Information
Related Material
Related material can be found in the papers of Dudley Harmon Sr. (father), housed in the Wesleyan University Archives. A copy of Storm Jameson's Farewell Night/Welcome Day inscribed to Dudley Harmon was transferred to the Mortimer Rare Book Room, Smith College.
- SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Dudley Harmon to Mr. Dudley Harmon (father) (others in family sometimes included), 1932-1953, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
  - Dudley Harmon to "all", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mr. Harmon to Dudley Harmon, 1932-1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dudley Harmon with Benjamin Fine, about his book Getting into College, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence to Dudley Harmon, 1953-1963, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence to Mr. Harmon, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- SERIES II. WRITINGS
  - Published newspaper and journal articles, 1933-62 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
  - Unpublished writings
    - Journal, Brazzaville, with attachments, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
    - Notes on economics (6 pages), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "Four Children": play, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Short stories: drafts (6), 1940s, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - European Communism: project description (incomplete draft), 1948 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Radio broadcasts on economic affairs (18), 1954 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Radio broadcasts on seamen's news from London, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- SERIES III. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL
  - Personal data, press releases, 1955, 1962, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, 1932-67, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 26-28)
  - Articles about her father, 1939, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Dudley Harmon alone and with others, 1930s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 30-31)
- SERIES V. MEMORABILIA
  - Invitations and programs, 1920-1960, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Scrapbooks (2), 1930-1952, n.d. (Box 2)